Everybody! Central Perk
is proud to present...
여러분!
센트럴 퍼크가 자랑하는
피비 부페이 양의 노래입니다
...the music of Miss Phoebe Buffay.
Thanks.
감사합니다
I wanna start with a song
that's about that moment...
오늘 노래는 우리 인생이
무엇인가에 관한 것입니다
...when you suddenly realize
what life is really all about.
Okay, here we go.
시작합니다
Okay. Thank you very much.
대단히 감사합니다
뭐야...
Oh, great. This is just
잘 됐군
이 꼴이 뭐...
The One With The Blackout
굉장하다!
온 도시가 정전됐어
This is so cool, you guys.
The entire city's blacked out.
It's all of Manhattan.
They have no idea...
맨하탄 전체와 브룩클린
일부가 정전인데
...when it's back on.
언제 복구될지 모른대
이거 사건이야
-You guys, this is big.
-Pants and a sweater. Why, Mom?
바지와 스웨터요?
왜요?
정전인데 데이트라뇨?
Who will I meet in a blackout?
전기 수리공?
우직한 도둑님?
Power-company guys?
Eligible looters?
나중에 다시 전화해요
-Can we talk about this later? Okay.
-Can I borrow the phone?
전화 좀 쓸게
할머니가 어떠신 지 궁금해서
I wanna call my apartment
and check on my grandma.
What's my number?
우리 집 번호가 뭐니?
I never call me.
나 자신에겐
전화 안 하잖아
Oh, my God! It's her.
It's that Victoria 's Secret model.
세상에! 웬 떡이냐
모델처럼 생겼네!
'구데이커' 같다
Something Goodacre.
Hi, Mom, it's Jill.
엄마!
질이에요
그래, 질 구데이커야!
She 's right. It's Jill.
Jill Goodacre. Oh, my God!
현금 입출금기 코너에서
질 구데이커와 갇히다니!
I am trapped in an A TM vestibule
with Jill Goodacre.
Is it a vestibule?
Maybe it's an atrium.
여기도 방은 방이지?
그것도 황제의 방!
Yeah, that is the part
to focus on, you idiot.
지금 그런 생각이 나냐?
멍청아!
I' m fine. I' m just stuck
at the bank in an ATM vestibule.
괜찮아요
은행에 갇혔어요
자동 인출기 있는 방이요
Jill says vestibule,
I'm going with vestibule.
방이랜다!
나와 같은 생각이군
I' m fine. No, l' m not alone.
괜찮아요, 혼자는 아니고...
I don't know, some guy.
몰라요, 어떤 남자요
Oh, some guy. I am some guy.
어떤 남자!
좋았어!
Jill, I saw you with some guy
last night.
안녕, 질
어제 밤에 어떤 남자랑 있더라
Yes, he was some guy.
내가 그 어떤 남자다
Hey, everyone.
안녕, 얘들아
Officiating at tonight's blackout
is Rabbi T ribbiani.
오늘 정전 미사는
트리비아니 님께서 집전하십니다
Chandler's old roommate was Jewish.
These are our only candles.
챈들러의 옛날 친구 쓰던 거고
이건 그냥 촛불이야
So happy Hanukkah!
기쁜 안식일!
봐! 벌거숭이 남자가
촛불을 엄청나게 켰어
Look! Ugly Naked Guy
lit a bunch of candles.
That had to hurt!
좀 뜨겁겠다
All right, all right!
It's been 14 1/2 minutes...
좋아요, 아주 좋아요!
14분 30초가 지났다
말 한마디도 없이!
...and you still haven 't said
one word. God!
Do something!
Just make contact. Smile!
뭐라고 하면서 접근을 해
웃어!
There you go.
잘한다
You 're definitely scaring her.
괜히 겁만 줬잖아
여보세요?
Hello? Oh, hi, Mom.
네, 엄마
그렇게 뛰지 마세요
Mom.
Mom, you' re tripping!
Dexter's a dog.
The blackout's scaring him.
덱스터는 개예요
어두워서 무섭나봐요
겁에 질리면 엄마도
아빠 신발에 쉬할 수 있죠
You'd pee in Dad's shoes too
if you didn't know.
All right, call me back.
다시 전화하세요
- 엄마들이란!
- 네
-Mothers.
-Yeah.
Attaboy! A word.
굉장하네요, 좋은 말이야
That wasn 't so hard.
Mothers. Yeah!
어렵지 않군, 엄마들이란!
엄마들이란! 그래
Mothers. Yeah! Perfect.
웃지마
Don 't smile.
Would you like to call somebody?
어디 전화할 데 있어요?
네!
학교 동창이 3백 명이죠
Yeah, about 300 guys I went
to high school with.
감사합니다
Yeah, thanks.
-Hello?
-It's me.
여보세요?
나야!
-It's Chandler. Are you okay?
-Yeah, l' m fine.
챈들러야
- 괜찮아?
- 응, 괜찮아
I' m stuck in an ATM vestibule...
현금 인출기 코너 방에 갇혔어
질 구데이커랑
...with Jill Goodacre.
-What?
-l' m stuck...
뭐?
질 구데이커랑
은행에 갇혔다구!
...in an ATM vestibule...
...with Jill Goodacre.
I have no idea what you said.
무슨 말인지 모르겠어
조이 바꿔 줘
Put Joey on the phone.
-What's up, man?
-l' m stuck...
무슨 일이야?
질 구데이커랑
은행에 갇혔어
...in an ATM vestibule...
...with Jill Goodacre!
Oh, my God!
세상에!
He's trapped in an ATM vestibule
with Jill Goodacre!
질 구데이커와
현금 인출기 코너에 갇혔대!
Chandler, listen.
챈들러, 잘 들어...
Like that thought
never entered my mind.
응, 그런 건 꿈도 못 꿔
- 다음, 다음
- 어서 해
-Okay.
-Somebody.
-I'll go. I'll go.
-Okay.
- 내가 할게
- 그래
대학 4학년 때 당구대 위!
Senior year of college,
on a pool table.
-Pool table?
-That's my sister.
당구대
제 여동생이죠!
가장 희한한 장소는...
Okay, my weirdest place
would have to be...
...the women's room of the New York
City Public Library.
뉴욕 공립 도서관
2층 여자 화장실에서!
세상에! 도서관에
뭐 하러 갔는데?
Oh, my God! What were you
doing in a library?
피비, 넌?
-Pheebs, what about you?
-Oh, Milwaukee.
밀워키
It's a really weird place.
정말 희한하지 않니?
Ross?
로스?
디즈니랜드...
1989년, 소인국 나라에서!
Disneyland, 1 989.
" It's a small world after all. "
- 말도 안돼!
- 그러게
No way.
놀이기구가 고장이 나서
캐롤과 꼬마인형 뒤에 숨었지
The ride broke down...
...so Carol and I went behind
those mechanical Dutch children.
기구가 다시 돌아가고, 들켜서
마술 왕국에도 못 갔어
We were asked never to return
to the Magic Kingdom.
그럼 이제 누가 남았지?
Let's see, that leaves....
그래, 레이첼
-Rachel?
-Come on, I already went.
난 벌써 했잖아
- 너 안 했어
- 말해봐
-You did not go.
-I did.
- 안 했어
- 해봐
T ell us. Come on.
그래...
가장 희한한 장소는...
All right, the weirdest place
would have to be...
...the foot of the bed.
침대 끝에서야!
- 다들 꼬리 내려라
- 네가 이겼다
-Step back!
-We have a winner!
This must be what the fridge
looks like with the door closed.
냉장고 안은 늘
이렇게 어두웠겠구나
으시시하다
Spooky.
배고픈 사람?
아이스크림이...
Anybody hungry?
We got a Klondike...soup.
죽이 됐네
I've never had a relationship
with that kind of passion.
난 그런 정열적인 사랑은
못해본 거 같아
놀이공원 한 가운데서
연인과 그랬다니!
Where you have to have somebody
even in a theme park.
It was the only thing to do
that didn't have a line.
줄이 길지만 않으면 가능해
Barry wouldn't even kiss me
on a miniature golf course.
베리는 미니 골프장에서
키스도 못하는 남자야
- 설마
- 진짜야
-Come on.
-No.
사람들에게 방해된다고
안 된대
He said we held up
the people behind us.
그럼 베리와 결혼하지
않은 이유가...?
You didn't marry him because...?
Do you think there are people
that go through life...
생각해봤어?
사람이 인생을 살면서
그런 감정도 없이...
... never having that kind of...?
- 가능해
- 그래?
-Probably.
-Really?
내 말 들어봐
열정은 과장된 감정이야
I'll tell you something.
Passion is way overrated.
-Yeah, right.
-lt is.
- 맞아
- 그렇지
Eventually, it kind of burns out.
결국엔 다 타버린다구
But hopefully what you're left
with is trust and security and....
모두 바라는 거지만
신뢰와 안정감이 필요해
In my ex-wife's case,
lesbianism.
내 전처는 동성에게
그걸 찾았지!
For those people who miss out
on that passion thing...
그러니까 그런 열정과
표현이 부족한 사람에게도
또 다른 좋은 점이 있어
...there's other stuff.
-Okay.
-But I don't think that'll be you.
알았어
그런데 넌 다른 것 같아
-You don't?
-See, I see...
그래?
있지...
-... big passion in your future.
-Really?
너는 앞으로
큰 열정에 빠질 거야
- 그럴까?
- 응
- 그래?
-You do?
-I do.
Ross, you' re so great.
로스...
참 좋은 남자야
It's never gonna happen.
절대로 안 될 거다
-What?
-You and Rachel.
뭐가?
너하고 레이첼
What? Me and Ra?
그게... 무슨...
Why not?
왜 안돼?
You waited too long
to make your move...
너무 시간을 끌어서
친구의 세계로 들어왔어
...and now you' re
in the "friend zone. "
-l' m not in the zone.
-No, Ross. You' re mayor of the zone.
그런 세계는 절대 아냐
로스!
넌 그 세계의 왕이야
Look, l' m taking my time, all right?
I' m laying the groundwork.
그저 천천히 할 뿐이야
기본 토대를 쌓는 거라구
Every day I get
a little bit closer to
매일 아주 조금씩 다가가는...
하느님께?
Priesthood!
I'm telling you, she has
no idea what you're thinking.
로스, 레이첼은 네가
어떤 생각을 하는지도 몰라
She just ran her fingers
through my hair.
그럴까?
내 머리를 쓰다듬었는데?
-Were you missing that interaction?
-No, no, no.
- 아까 그거 못 봤니?
- 그건 아냐
This is running fingers
through your hair, okay?
이건 애정이 담긴 거고...
이건 꼬마한테 하는 거야
Now this is a tousle.
If you don't ask her out soon,
you'll be in the zone forever.
빨리 데이트 신청 안 하면
그 '친구 세계'에 영원히 갇힐 거야
할거야, 내가 기다리는 건...
적당한 때야
I will, I will.
I'm waiting for the right moment.
- 뭐? 지금?
- 당연하지
What?
-What, now?
-Yeah.
지금 얼마나 좋으냐?
포도주, 촛불, 달빛...
What's messing you up?
The wine? The moonlight?
그냥 다가가서 말만 해
레이첼, 난 말이야...
You gotta go up to her and say,
" Look, Rachel, l"
왜들 쉬쉬해?
-What?
-We' re shushing...
쉬... 라고 한 건
무슨 소리가 들려서 그래
... because we' re trying
to hear something.
소리?
-What? What?
-Don't you hear that?
안 들려?
맞지?
See?
-Would you like gum?
-ls it sugarless?
껌 드릴까요?
무설탕이죠?
- 아닌데요
- 그럼 사양할게요
-Sorry, it's not.
-Then no, thanks.
이게 무슨 짓이야?
What was that?
천하의 질 구데이커가
껌을 권하면 받아야지!
Mental note: If Jill Goodacre
offers you gum, you take it.
If she offers you mangled
animal carcass, you take it!
죽은 고양이 시체를 줘도
기쁘게 받아야지!
New York City has no power
뉴욕 시에 전기가 나갔네
And the milk is getting sour
그리고 우유가 상해가네
하지만 난 두렵지 않네
But to me it is not scary
Because I stay away from dairy
난 유제품이 싫으니까
-Here goes.
-You'll do it?
- 좋아, 한다
- 정말 할거지?
-I'll do it.
-Want help?
- 정말 한다니까
- 도와줄까?
한 발이라도 나오면
넌 죽음이야
You come out, you' re a dead man.
로스!
-Good luck, man.
-Thanks.
행운을 빈다, 임마
고마워
-Okay.
- 좋아, 좋아
- 그래
Where you going?
You can't go out there.
- 너 어디 가니?
- 밖에
안돼! 나가면 안돼
-Why not?
-Because of the reason.
- 왜?
- 왜냐하면...
이유가 있지!
-That would be?
-I can't tell you.
그 이유는?
말... 못하는 이유
Joey, what's going on?
무슨 일이야?
그럼 절대로 오빠한테
내가 말했다고 하지마
You gotta promise you'll
never tell Ross that I told you.
-What?
-He's planning your birthday party.
뭔데?
네 생일 파티를 계획중이야
-Oh, my God! I love him!
-You better act surprised.
세상에, 역시 최고야!
놀라는 연습이나 해둬
-About what?
-My surprise party.
뭘 놀래?
- 내 깜짝 파티
- 무슨 깜짝 파티?
-What surprise party?
-Oh, stop it. Joey already told me.
모른 체 하지마
조이한테 들었어
He didn't tell me.
난 왜 모르니?
Don't look at me. This is Ross' thing.
나 쳐다보지마
로스 계획이야
This is typical.
I'm always the last to know.
맨날 이 모양이야
난 왜 꼭 맨 끝에 알지?
아냐, 다 말해주잖아
You are not. We tell you stuff.
그래?
I was the last one to know when
Chandler got bit by the peacock.
챈들러가 동물원에서
새한테 물린 것도 그렇고
조이가 이사올 때, 네가
반한 것도 맨 끝에 알았어
I was the last to know
you had a crush on Joey.
뭐?
What?
Looks like I was second to last.
나 말고도 모르는 사람이 있네
나한테 반했었다구?
You had a crush on me?
All right. It wasn't a crush,
it was a dent.
반한 건 아니고
좀 인상적이었어
많이?
Big dent?
You were moving your furniture.
I thought you had nice arms.
가구를 옮길 때였어
팔의 근육이 멋지더라구
그것 뿐이야
Nice arms, huh?
팔의 근육?
모니카, 나 지금
의자 옮긴다
Hey, Mon, l' m moving the chair.
Do anything for you?
지금도 인상적이니?
With all the lights out
you can actually see the stars.
도시의 조명이 없으니까
별이 잘 보이네
너무 좋다
It's so nice.
I have a question.
물어볼 게 있어
그렇게 큰 일은 아니고
그저... 일반적인 거야
Actually, it's not
so much a question.
It's more
of a general wondering....
ment.
그런데...
-Okay.
-Okay. Here it goes.
- 그런데?
- 그래
말할게
꽤 오랫동안 원한 건데...
Well, for a while now,
I've been wanting to....
-Yes, that's right.
-Look at that little kitty!
그래, 맞아!
저기 새끼 고양이 좀 봐
뭐?
What?
Top of the world
Looking down on creation
난 세상의 꼭대기에 있어요
만물을 굽어보며
내가 찾은 답은 하나죠
And the only explanation I can find
당신을 만난 후
사랑이란 걸 찾게 됐어요...
Is the love that I found
Ever since you 've been around
당신의 사랑은
이 세상 무엇보다 소중하죠
All right, this is just Bactine.
It won't hurt.
그냥 연고야, 아프지 않아
-Ow!
-Sorry, that was wax.
미안, 촛농이 떨어졌어
불쌍한 새끼 고양이가
겁먹었어, 주인을 찾아주자
Poor little T ooty's scared.
We should find his owner.
그냥 복도에 내놓지 그래?
Why not put poor T ooty in the hall?
During a blackout?
She'll get trampled.
이렇게 깜깜한데?
그러다 밟히면 어떡해?
Yeah?
그래?
Damage control. Get back to the gum.
좋아, 이미지 되찾기!
다시 껌 얘기!
Gum would be perfection.
다시 생각해보니
껌이 아주 좋겠어요
껌이 아주 좋아?
무슨 말이 그래
Gum would be perfection?
Gum would be perfection.
Could've said,
"Gum would be nice. " But, no.
그냥 "껌 주실래요?"
아니면 "나중에 사드리죠"
아냐, 아냐
그냥 '껌이 좋아요'가 낫다
For me, gum is perfection.
I loathe myself!
내 자신이 왜 이리
징하냐!
Oh, no, they' re nuns.
They hate all living things.
거긴 수녀가 살아
동물을 싫어한대
그래?
Hi. We just found this cat,
and we' re looking for the owner.
안녕하세요?
고양이 주인을 찾고 있어요
Yeah, it's mine.
네, 제 겁니다
얘가 별로 안 반기는데
정말이세요?
-He seems to hate you. Are you sure?
-It's my cat. Give me my cat.
내 고양이에요
이리 줘요
잠깐요, 얘 이름이 뭐죠?
-Wait a minute. What's his name?
-Bob Buttons.
밥... 버튼즈요
-Bob Buttons?
-Bob Buttons. Here, Bob Buttons.
밥 버튼즈?
밥 버튼즈
이리와, 버튼즈!
You are a very bad man!
- 그러시는 거 아니에요
- 기막혀!
You owe me a cat.
나중에 돈으로 갚아요
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
야옹아, 야옹아
Here, kitty, kitty.
Where did you go, little kitty?
어디 갔니?
야옹아, 야옹아
IKitty, kitty, kitty.
Come here, kitty, kitty.
이리 온
야옹아, 야옹아, 야옹아
야옹아, 야옹아, 야옹아...
-Hi.
-Buona sera.
안녕하세요?
부오나 세라!
Wow!
Mon, wanna go for a ride
in my racecar?
모니카, 나랑 드라이브 갈래?
내 팔도 가져갈게
I'll bring my arms.
We can bring my wheelbarrow
for your teeth!
그래, 좋아
내 손수건도 가져가자
코피 나면 닦아줄게
Come on, lucky sixes!
6만 나와라!
얘들아, 여긴 파올로야
파올로, 친구들이에요
Everybody, this is Paolo.
Paolo, I want you to meet my friends.
This is Monica...
여긴 모니카
안녕하세요?
-Hi.
-...and Joey...
여긴 조이
안녕하세요?
-Hi.
-...and Ross.
여긴 로스
Hi.
안녕하세요?
영어를 잘 못한대
He doesn't speak much English.
모노폴리!
Monopoly!
이런 것도 아네!
Look at that!
파올로는 어디서 왔어?
So, where did Paolo come from?
이탈리아, 아마도
Italy, I think.
아니, 어디서 나왔냐구?
불쑥 우리 생활에 끼어들다니
No, I mean tonight.
Suddenly, into our lives.
That cat turned out to be Paolo's cat.
Isn't that funny?
그 고양이 주인이 파올로였어
신기하지?
진짜 신기한 건, 레이첼이
계속 저 남자를 만지는 거야
That is funny.
And Rachel keeps touching him.
I looked all over and couldn't find
the kitty anywhere.
건물을 다 뒤졌는데
어디에도 없어
I found him. It was Paolo's cat.
찾았어
파올로 고양이래
잘됐네, 이번에도
맨 끝에 아는군
Well, there you go.
Last to know again.
게다가 이젠 소개도
안 시켜주네, 파올로?
And I'm guessing, this is Paolo?
파올로, 여긴 피비야
Paolo, this is Phoebe.
피비...
물론이죠
You betcha!
좋아, 이젠 뭐지?
All right. Okay. What next?
풍선을 불어볼까?
그게 좋겠어
Blow a bubble. A bubble's good.
It's got a boyish charm. It's impish.
남자답게 보이지
개구쟁이처럼!
해보자
Here we go.
잘했다, 개구쟁이!
괜찮아, 괜찮을 거야
Nice going, imp!
It's okay. All I need to do...
이제 할 일은 다시
입에 넣고 씹는 거야
...is reach over and put it
back in my mouth.
Good save!
We 're back on track and I'm...
잘했어!
다시 제자리로 왔어
... chewing someone else 's gum.
그런데 뭔가...
다른 사람이 씹던 껌인가?
This is not my gum!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
아까랑 촉감이 달라
세상에! 하느님!
And now you 're choking.
목에 걸렸다!
You all right?
괜찮아요?
My God! You' re choking!
세상에, 목에 걸렸군요?
-Better?
-Yes.
괜찮죠?
네
Thank you. That was....
고마워요
지금 기분이...
-That was....
-Perfection?
아주 좋죠?
That was no tousle.
저게 진짜 쓰다듬는 거다
-What'd he say that was so funny?
-I have absolutely no idea.
뭐 신기한 말이라도 했어?
정말 하나도 모르겠어
That's classic.
그거야 뻔하지!
얘들아, 내가 왜 이러니?
이건 나답지 않아
My God, you guys! What am I doing?
This is so un-me!
If you want, I'll do it.
네가 싫다면, 내가 할게
저 남자 입술이
너무 섹시해
I just wanna bite his bottom lip.
But I won't.
안 쳐다볼게
The first time he smiled at me...
베리와 여행 갔던 3주보다
저 남자와 눈이 마주친
3초가 더 흥분돼
...those seconds were more exciting
than weeks with Barry.
거기서 자전거 타봤니?
Did you rent mopeds?
Because I've heard
Oh, it's not about that right now.
내가 듣기로는...
지금 그 얘기할 때가
아니구나
I know it's superficial,
and we have nothing in common...
완전히 겉만 보고 빠졌어
공통점도 없고, 말도 안 통하는데
...and we don't even speak
the same language, but, God!
아이구, 하느님...
-Paolo, hi.
-Ross.
파올로, 있죠...
로스
잘 들어요
Listen....
Listen, something you should know.
있잖아요
알아둘 게 있어요
Rachel and I are....
레이첼과 나는...
We' re kind of a thing.
어떤... 사이에요
-Thing?
-Thing. Yes, thing.
- 사이요?
- 네, 사이요
-You have the sex?
-No.
- 같이 잤나요?
- 아뇨
No, technically the sex
is not being had. But that's....
아니죠, 육체적인 접촉이
있는 사이는 아니지만...
But that's not the point.
그런 말이 아니고...
중요한 건, 레이첼과 내가...
The point is that
Rachel and I should be....
Well, Rachel and l
should be together.
레이첼과 내가 앞으로
사귀게 될 거예요
만일 당신이 끼여들면...
And if you get in the
-ln bed
-No.
- 침대에?
- 아뇨!
No, not where I was going.
거기 끼는 거 말구요
If you get in the way of us
becoming a thing...
미래의 우리 관계에 끼여들면
난 아주 슬플 거예요
...then I would be, well, very sad.
So, do you...?
- 그러니까 당신이...
- 알겠어요
- 알아요?
- 알죠
영어를 쬐금 알긴 아는군요?
-So you do know a little English?
-Little.
조금이요
- 그럼 '멍청이'란 말 알아요?
- 아뇨
-Do you know the word "crap-weasel "?
-No.
몰라요? 재밌네요
당신이 바로 그 '멍청이'인데!
That's funny.
You are a huge crap-weasel.
고마워요
이걸 1시간 째 하고 있어요
잘 봐요, 쉬워요
We've been doing this
for an hour. It's easy.
- 네
- 준비?
Ready?
Okay? Now try it.
봤죠? 해봐요
힘껏 돌려야죠
You gotta whip it.
Look, look. The last candle's
about to burn out.
이거 봐! 마지막 초가
꺼지려고 해
10, 9, 8, 7
T en, nine, eight, seven...
... minus 46, minus 47,
minus 48....
- 46, - 47, - 48...
-Thank you.
-Thanks.
- 고맙다
- 고마워
IKind of spooky without any lights.
깜깜하니까 좀 무섭다
Okay, guys, I have the definitive one.
다들 조용해!
내가 결정판을 들려줄게
This probably isn't the best time
to bring it up...
지금 이런 말 하긴
그렇지만...
...but you have to throw
a party for Monica.
모니카 생일파티는 해야돼
- 정말 재밌었어요
- 네
-This has been fun.
-Yes.
Thanks for letting me
use your phone...
전화 빌려줘서 고마웠어요
생명을 구해준 것두요
...and for saving my life.
잘 가요, 챈들러
즐거운 정전사고였어요
Well, goodbye, Chandler.
I had a great blackout.
안녕!
See you.
안녕하세요? 계좌번호
7143457입니다
Hi, l' m account number 71 43457.
I don't know if you got that...
감시카메라가 잘 돌아갔는지
모르겠지만...
... but I would really
like a copy of the tape.
테입 좀 복사해주세요